<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.calstfrancis.Iskra</id>
  <name>Iskra</name>
  <summary>Sermon planning for preachers who work from structured notes</summary>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>
      Iskra (Искра, "spark") is a sermon-planning tool built around structured
      notes rather than a full manuscript: jot single-line ideas, expand any of
      them with longer notes, group them into movements, drag everything into
      order, tag it, and export a clean outline for Rubric's sermon field.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Idea bars with click-to-edit text, expandable notes, and idea/part tags</li>
      <li>Movements to group ideas, with drag-and-drop reordering within and between them</li>
      <li>Continuous auto-numbering across the whole sermon</li>
      <li>Revised Common Lectionary readings, season, and liturgical colour resolved from the planned date</li>
      <li>Sermon library with search by title, tags, and date</li>
      <li>Undo/redo covering every structural and text edit</li>
      <li>Git sync — commit and push to all remotes in one click; sign in with GitHub via device flow</li>
      <li>Export to a format Rubric imports directly into its sermon field</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.calstfrancis.Iskra.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/calstfrancis/iskra</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/calstfrancis/iskra/issues</url>
  <developer_name>Cal St Francis</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Planning a sermon's movements and ideas</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/calstfrancis/iskra/main/screenshots/iskra-main.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>
          Kindled Verse — scripture citations with live autocomplete (type
          <code>@john3:16</code> to tag and cite a reference, with a
          Bibliography section in Preaching View and Print), a printable
          Preaching View, movement split/merge, multi-select ideas, and a
          batch of workflow shortcuts and visual polish.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>
          First Light — the first release. Sermon templates, a large-print
          chrome-free Preaching View, an in-app history browser backed by
          git, sermon series grouping, quick-pick tag chips, and a batch of
          drag-and-drop and git sync robustness fixes.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
